[ONYANKOPON] The plan failed.
Why does it always end this way?
Violence will always be
a part of human existence,
won't it, Captain?
Why are you betraying us?
I don't understand, Conny!
We were supposed to be on
the same side, no matter what!
We still are on
the same side, Samuel!
[CONNY]
But I... I just!
[JAEGERIST 86B screams]
[Roars]
What?
Back up. Say that again.
I'm sorry, but it's the truth.
We need an entire day
to service the boat
before it will be able to fly.
That time can probably be cut in
half with the right equipment,
but even that
might be a stretch.
Are you kidding me?
You mean we have to
hold off the enemy
for half a day while you work?
You do realize
reinforcements are coming.
There's no way we can protect
you and the port that long.
Our Titans are only able to
fight for a few hours at a time.
[HANGE]
We'll be too late.
[HANGE] The rumbling can
outpace a sprinting horse,
and there isn't a single
obstacle out there
that can slow it down.
It's an unyielding
wave of destruction.
Half a day from now, they'll be
600 kilometers inland.
Nothing in their
path will survive.
[HANGE] They could flatten the
entire continent in four days.
Four days.
That's all it'll take.
[KIYOMI gasps]
[HANGE] Even if we launch the
ship and manage to stop Eren...
...Liberio will still fall.
There's no way to save it.
[Gasps]
Dammit.
We still don't know
Eren's location.
And time is working against us.
More are dying each second.
And regardless,
we've got no chance
of holding out long enough
to ready the ship.
There's no way.
[KIYOMI]
I have an idea.
[KIYOMI] Odiha is
a coastal city in Marley
some distance to the south.
We own and operate
a hanger there.
If we can reach it,
it'll be an ideal servicing
station for the flying boat.
I think we should
set sail for that hangar now
and tow the boat behind us.
Then we can finish prepping it
for flight on the continent,
under more favorable conditions.
[HANGE] Interesting.
A city on the coast, huh?
Hold on, isn't it about to be
wiped out by the rumbling?
We would beat the Titans there.
But I don't know
how much time we'd have
before they caught up.
I can only say that
we'd be cutting it close.
This would be a gamble.
[HANGE]
A gamble.
Whatever the case,
clearly we won't be
flying from this port.
Does the ship have fuel?
Uh, yes!
But it'll take 30 minutes
to ready the boiler.
[MAGATH] Make it 15!
If you screw up and die here,
then Hizuru and the rest of
the world are doomed!
So stay sharp!
[HIZURU ENVOY]
Right!
I'll go inform
Levi and the others.
[HANGE] And I'll do
the same with Mikasa!
♪ Opening Song ♪
[JAEGERISTS groan]
[JAEGERIST 86H]
You bitch!
Have to change plans.
We'll sail out of here and prep
the flying boat on the mainland.
The mainland? All right.
[MIKASA]
Help them board that ship!
Faster! Go!
It's the Azumabito
mechanics! Kill them!
[HANGE yells]
I'll kill you!
You damn traitors!
[FLOCH] Why'd they
leave the safety of cover?
What could be worth
taking that risk?
[Gasps]
[FLOCH]
No way.
Reiner!
[REINER TITAN roars]
[JAEGERIST 86L]
No! Please!
Don't stop moving!
[JAEGERIST 86P yells]
[JAEGERIST 86Q]
Forget the Female Titan!
Kill the Azumabito!
[ANNIE groans]
[MAGATH] Get up!
We're nearly there, so go!
[JAEGERIST 86V]
Take her down!
[FLOCH]
Dammit. I don't believe this.
They're actually planning
to try to make a break
for the mainland?
[REINER TITAN groans]
[FLOCH]
Bring every last Thunder Spear!
They plan on using
that ship to get to Eren.
So make sure it never
leaves this dock.
If they reach Eren and kill him,
then Paradis will drown
in a sea of blood.
The world will seek revenge
and butcher your parents,
your siblings,
and every kid on this island.
Your hearts and souls,
to the cause!
Oh, no.
[ONYANKOPON]
It looks like the Jaegerists
are aiming for the boat.
Our Titans won't last long.
Not if they keep on
taking shots like that.
[REINER TITAN groans]
I should be fighting with them.
I can use the power
of the Jaw Titan.
[PIECK TITAN]
Bad idea.
First transformations
never go well.
[FALCO]
But at this rate--
Leave the fight to me.
After I get you all onto the
ship, I'll back up the others.
I'm so useless.
If only it were Galliard here.
[FALCO] He wouldn't be
sitting on his hands
wondering what to do.
[GABI]
No! Come back!
Don't follow.
I need to drop you all
off on that ship.
[MAGATH] Quickly!
Get that boiler going!
Huh?
[MAGATH]
Conny!
Armin was shot in the chest.
And the face, too.
He should heal fast,
though. Can you--?
[CONNY]
I'll guard the ship!
[PIECK TITAN]
Commander, Falco's out there.
[Gasps]
[HANGE gasps]
Reinforcements! Dammit.
Unless we do
something about them,
we'll be killed along with
most of humanity.
[HANGE gasps]
We needed those reinforcements.
How'd they take the train out?
[JEAN] What are you doing,
Falco? Get on the ship!
[FALCO]
Right!
[Gasps]
[REINER]
My body--it won't move!
[ANNIE]
Can't see anything.
This is it! Finish them off!
[CONNY yells]
Conny!
Piece of shit traitor.
Just die already!
Conny!
[JEAN]
Hesitate...
[MIKASA] ...for even a second,
and your comrades die.
[JAEGERISTS scream]
What now, Floch?
We keep fighting!
We still have the tools
to take these traitors down.
Attack in unison! Nail the Cart
with Thunder Spears!
Back off! Damn!
[FLOCH] We'll stop them.
Even if it costs us our lives!
'Cause our country
is worth dying for!
[FALCO TITAN roars]
--[FALCO TITAN roars]
--It's Falco!
[JAEGERISTS groan]
[Roars]
Falco!
Come on! They're
out of formation,
so this is our chance!
Now or never!
[MIKASA grunts]
[Roars]
[Yells]
[FLOCH]
It all comes down to this shot.
If I can just put a hole
in the ship, then we win.
[PIECK gasps]
[Gasps]
[FLOCH] I'm gonna save
the Eldian Empire. Right now!
[JAEGERIST 86AQ]
Floch!
[JAEGERIST 86AS screams]
[MIKASA grunts]
[JAEGERIST 86AW gasps]
[JAEGERISTS screaming]
We're ready to sail!
Come aboard!
[HANGE]
Let's go. Quick.
Before they have
time to regroup.
[JEAN gasps]
[JEAN]
Watch it!
[Roars]
Falco!
The enemy's retreating!
Come out!
[Gasps]
[MAGATH]
Pieck! Hold him still!
[Gasps]
Falco, stop!
[MAGATH]
You're okay. I got you.
Rest up for now,
you've earned it.
Take him.
Of course.
Tell them to set out.
Huh? Aren't you coming?
No, I need to hold the rear.
We're really lucky
the commander got to him.
Yeah.
Things were looking
pretty bleak back there.
Hey, wait a sec.
Where is the commander?
It's "General" now.
[JAEGERIST 86AZ]
Enemy spotted!
One stayed behind. Get him!
[JAEGERISTS groan]
[MAGATH]
You're the one who took out
their reinforcements,
aren't you?
[KEITH]
I am.
Why didn't you take to sea
with the others?
[MAGATH] That floating giant's
a captured Marleyan cruiser.
It's fast enough to
catch up with their ship
and sink them along with
humanity's hopes.
I can't allow that.
Need to put it
underwater somehow.
I'll give you a hand.
They'll be here soon.
Let him come.
This'll be ready to blow
before they can break in.
Last chance for you
to take a swim.
No. I'll stay.
I've been looking for
a good end to this life.
What made you decide
to help us out?
There's a chance that
you've doomed your island.
Saw some former
students of mine.
Traveling south
out of Shiganshina.
Annie Leonhart was with them.
When I realized what
their plan was, I was moved.
And I was proud to see
how much they'd grown.
[MAGATH] If you hadn't stopped
that train, they'd be dead.
And they're not
the only ones in your debt.
When the dust settles,
you'll be known as one of the
heroes who saved the world.
Well, then,
that makes two of us.
[MAGATH] I've done nothing
to be proud of.
I served my country by
ignoring my conscience.
They were innocent kids
till I got ahold of them and
turned them into soldiers.
I ordered them to
breach those walls.
[MAGATH] It's far too late,
but I've finally realized
how happy I would've been...
...if those kids could've
lived normal lives.
[KEITH] Well, you might not
think you deserve it, but still,
I've got plenty respect for you.
You there! Stop!
Open this door, dammit!
What are you doing in there?
And those kids would
probably say the same.
So...
Thank you.
Before I shoot, who are you?
My name is Keith Shadis.
And what's yours?
Theo Magath.
[Inaudible]
♪ Ending Song ♪
[HANGE] We conferred with Magath
and decided to head for Odiha.
Though, to be perfectly honest,
we didn't have any other option.
[HANGE] I'm afraid this means
we can't save your hometown.
Liberio's doomed. I'm sorry.
[ANNIE]
If that's true, I'm done.
The only reason I had
to keep fighting is gone.
[ANNIE]
I'm getting off the ship.
[HANGE]
Even if all went well
and we stopped
the rumbling in its tracks,
Liberio and Marley were always
going to be trampled flat.
Magath understood that.
Yet he chose to give his life
so we'd have the chance
to push forward.
He died, not for
Liberio or for Marley,
but in the hopes that
it would help us save
at least one more stranger,
whose name he'll never know.
[ANNIE] In that case, I'll ask
you this question once more.
Be honest. You think
you can kill Eren?
[ANNIE]
Think hard.
If I try to kill him,
what will you do?
Can you sit by and watch?
Cause...
I'm sick of this.
I'm so tired.
I don't want to fight anymore.
[ANNIE]
Not with any of you.
Not even with Eren.
[NARRATOR]
The events witnessed that day.
The ideas exchanged.
The choices made.
All of it happened
in accordance with his will.
Next episode:
"The Dawn of Humanity."